I started listening to Green Lights and
I was told you had to listen to it cuz
of course he reads it. So this anecdotes
from when he was like 20, 21. He'd
gotten into the University of Texas, he
was pre-law. He had met some people at
Texas that had convinced him that he
should switch to film school and he had
immense anxiety about sharing this with
his father, but he finally tells his dad
and his dad utters this very simple
phrase, well, don't half-ass it.
He says of all the reactions he could
have had, don't half-ass it were the
last words I expected to hear and the
best words he could have ever said to
me. And he said in that single moment he
gave him a blessing, consent, approval,
validation, privilege, honor, freedom
and responsibility. Called it rocket
fuel.